# Ohood Awad Hamza

# DATA ANALYTICS SPECIALIST

### **OBJECTIVE**

Highly analytical Data Analyst, passionate customer experience analyst in technology and communication, with over a year of experience in digital marketing. Possess analytical skills in analyzing customer data, generating reports, and customer journey design. Deadline-driven technical thinking with advanced knowledge of Excel, PowerPoint presentations, and data visualization by Power BI and Tableau. In previous roles, I excelled at driving customer loyalty and improving customer retention rates, and developing insights that lead to actionable recommendations.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's degree in Information Technology, Faculty of Mathematical Sciences and Informatics, University of Khartoum. 2021

#### CONTACT



+249127853256



awadohood930@gmail.com



Omdurman, Khartoum, Sudan



ohood-awad-b6a79b139

# **LANGUGE**

Arabic: NativeEnglish: Good

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Customer Experience Analytics
MTN Sudan | June 2022-present

Analyzed customer feedback and data to identify trends, opportunities for improvement, and areas of strength to drive continuous improvement across the organization. I have developed a deep understanding of customers' needs by analyzing qualitative and quantitative research findings from multiple sources including focus groups, surveys, interviews, etc.

Communicated key insights through presentations to executive leadership as well as through reports that were shared with cross-functional teams throughout the company. Responsible for creating and maintaining monthly reports for VOC (Call Centre, Customer Complaint, Retail, FCR & CRM), account Net Promoter Score (NPS), Committee reports, and ad-hoc requests.

Teaching Assistant (part-time)
University of Khartoum August 2022-present

Worked as a teaching assistant at the university of Khartoum. A core group of 60+ students was directed for a college semester.

Digital Marketing Specialist (remote work)
Accel for ERP and Software Solutions | Jan 2022 - May

Worked as a Digital Marketing Specialist at Accel, starting with strategy development and target customer identification, content planning and development, writing and publishing, as well as campaigns, analysis, and reporting.

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Analytical thinking.
- Teaching.
- Critical Thinking.
- Problem Solving.
- Presentation Skills
- Communication Skills.
- Time management and organization.
- Strategic thinking.
- Creative Thinking.
- Public Speaking.

#### TECHNICALL SKILLS

- Data Analysis (collecting, cleaning, and data modeling).
- Data Mining.
- Data Visualization: Power BI, Tableau.
- Reporting and dashboard.
- Customer Experience Measurement.
- Key performance indicators Analysis.
- Microsoft Office: Excel (advanced), PowerPoint.
- Manage databases: SQL, SQL Server.
- Programming languages such as Python
- Digital Marketing: B2B, B2C.
- · Content Writing.

#### **INTEREST**

- Customer Experience.
- Data Science.
- Business Intelligence.
- Blockchain.
- Data Journalism.

#### **REFREVCE**

Mohammed Khalid Hassan

Teacher at the University of Khartoum, Faculty of Mathematical Sciences and Informatics.

Tel: +249912171785

Reel Kamaleldin Elzain

Customer Experience Analysis Manager at MTN Sudan

Tel: +249922902775

## WORK EXPERIENCE ——

 Social Media Marketing and Content Writing <u>Colors Services Agency, 2021 - 2022</u>

Worked as a content writer for Colors Services and several other clients such as Rodud and Appness for various social media platforms. Starting from developing a strategy, planning and developing the content, then writing and publishing it, and then analyzing it and writing the report

## <u>Training</u>

 Business intelligence at Al Baraka Bank -Sudan, March 2022 - April 2022

During the training period at Al Baraka Bank in the IT department, in the Business Intelligence department, I learned how to work with data, what is ETL (Extract, Transform, and Load), and how it works.

I worked with Excel, SQL, and SQL Server and got to know their concepts and how they work (SSIS, SSAS, SSRS). In addition to dealing with visual studio and Power BI.

- Social media marketing at Orooma, 2019.
- Customer Service at Al Baraka Bank Sudan, 2016.

## Volunteering

- School Student Exhibition "SSE", content writing, 2020.
- Global Entrepreneurship week "GEW", event team 2018.
- Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers "IEEE" Sudan. Jan – Dec 2017.
- Parallel School "Public Relations team". May 2017.
- Human Library "Development and Public Relations team". Oct 2017 – Feb 2018.

#### CERTIFICATION

#### Coursera Online platform | 2022

- Excel Skills for Business.
- Business Analysis and Process Management.
- Database Design with SQL Server Management Studio.
- Build Dashboard in Power BI.

#### Udacity Online platform | 2020

• Data Analysis.

#### Edraak Online platform | 2020

• Digital Marketing.